<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Bryce McDonnell - Business</title>
		<description>Posts categorized with 'business'</description>
		<link>http://www.brycemcdonnell.com</link>
		<atom:link href="http://www.brycemcdonnell.com/feed.business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>The Difference Between A Chief Technology Officer And Great Engineer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had the pleasure of meeting with many Chief Technology Officers (CTOs) 
lately.  All have been very bright individuals and I
love living in a city this dense with smart technologists who are willing to be
so collaborative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am noticing a trend in two general types of CTO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The engineering master&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The general generalist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particularly in product or app driven companies, the CTO role is filled
by an early engineer who is very good at writing software and
scaling the engineering culture. The general generalist is usually a
good engineer but has had a lot of experience in other areas of
technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having broad technology experience, as in the case of the general generalist,
makes for a technology leader who is better able to scale the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;qualities-of-the-general-generalist&quot;&gt;Qualities of The General Generalist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The General Generalist is able to lead in at least three capacities in their role as
the company’s chief technologist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software engineering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internal IT, networking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These abilities are in addition to having a strong business
background.&lt;/strong&gt; A CTO must be able to contribute to developing the
strategy of the business. Big impacts in this area are key to being an
effective CTO versus an outstanding technologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;engineering-leadership&quot;&gt;Engineering Leadership&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software engineering has become more dominant in the success of
businesses in the last ten years or so. While it’s still relatively
difficult to hire great engineering talent, there is a cadre of
individuals with very strong backgrounds in engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be a successful CTO leading engineering, the leader must be familiar
with the engineering practices that will create competitive advantages
with the culture of their company. Engineers write high quality and well tested
code with a strong review process and simple release schedule.
Appreciating and fostering these skills within the organization is
an important leadership trait required to be an effective CTO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own background is in engineering, and I think many CTOs today excel
at this aspect of their role. Engineering is only one facet of leading the business.
Even when the principle product is an app of some kind, the business will have to
scale. A CTO who only has experience in engineering will struggle with
other aspects of whole company leadership like scaling the internal
team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;internal-it-leadership&quot;&gt;Internal IT Leadership&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scaling the internal team applies to the engineering team but also the
technology requirements of scaling the marketing, art and finance
departments. To be really effective as a CTO means to be effective in
leading the technology requirements of the internal office. In this
sense, it also means leveraging technology to make internal processes
efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laptops, file sharing and effortless remote collaboration all contribute to
lowered overhead and fall squarely in the realm of CTO responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many CTOs I know hate this aspect of technology and want to just have it
take care of itself. I understand this view, but excelling in providing
leadership in this area is a key difference in the VP Engineering and
CTO. Both are executive level roles, but the VP is slightly more
specialized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managing the internal technology requirements is opportunity for creating
competitive advantages for your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-leadership&quot;&gt;Data Leadership&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An emerging trend for companies is to build data driven experiences. For many
companies, managing and integrating data is a new competency and
requires a lot of technical systems. For this reason, data wrangling
(and sometimes data science) is a responsibility of the technology
group of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to lead decision making with data and leverage data across
the whole organization is probably a major differentiator in good and
amazing CTOs these days. I predict this trend will change over time and
managing data will become table stakes for CTOs of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New technologies are emerging that manage, transform and report on data.
CTOs should be aware of these technologies and leverage them to drive
value in their businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exceptions&quot;&gt;Exceptions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The size of the company often comes in to play when considering a CTO.
Indeed internal IT and data concerns can fall into the realm of the
chief information officer. While this is true of large organizations (CIOs
aren’t usually hired in small or medium companies), I
still think being able to lead these initiatives is an important quality
of being a good CTO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other qualities that are important to a CTO that I haven’t elaborated on
in this article but are nonetheless important (and probably deserving of
their own blog post):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fostering a strong technology culture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communicating your company’s tech culture to the public&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having an appreciation of the concerns outside the technology
department&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identifying changes in the business and technology landscape and
creating opportunities within the company&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business acumen like reading and managing profit &amp;amp; loss and balance
sheet reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-end&quot;&gt;The End&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competencies of CTOs have expanded and will continue to do so. It’s one
of the many reasons that leading technology is so invigorating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, tweet &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/brycemcd&quot;&gt;@brycemcd&lt;/a&gt; with thoughts
comments and alternative viewpoints.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.brycemcdonnell.com/business/2015/10/21/the-difference-between-a-chief-technology-officer-and-great-engineer.html?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_medium=blogrss</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.brycemcdonnell.com/business/2015/10/21/the-difference-between-a-chief-technology-officer-and-great-engineer.html?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_medium=blogrss</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Plotting User Retention Curves In R</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post was inspired by Dan Croak (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Croaky&quot;&gt;@croaky&lt;/a&gt;)
 over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://robots.thoughtbot.com/create-a-retention-curve-with-mixpanel-and-google-sheets&quot;&gt;The Giant Robots Blog&lt;/a&gt;.
His approach to user retention is spot-on and his walk through for user
retention graphs are very useful for building a consumer facing product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brycemcd/status/617433218627858432&quot;&gt;I tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that
a user retention curve is easier to explain to other people in the
business in a way that is actionable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Create a Retention Curve with Mixpanel and Google Sheets -
much easier to grok than the waterfall charts imho &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/NvWfUFfHSV&quot;&gt;https://t.co/NvWfUFfHSV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash;
Bryce (@brycemcd) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/brycemcd/status/617433218627858432&quot;&gt;July 4,
2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking this one step further, I think that building such a curve should
be mindless to generate. Dan’s tutorial was straightforward but making
it automatic will decrease the time to generate the graph. Making a user
retention graph a no-brainer will make it much more likely that it gets
generated at a regular interval and shared with other people in the
business. In particular, manually changing the colors and building a
graph in Google Sheets is fairly arduous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moar-automation&quot;&gt;MOAR AUTOMATION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan’s (and now my) goal of producing user retention curves can be better
automated. All it takes is R (or RStudio) and the downloaded csv from
Mixpanel (see Dan’s post for the format of the csv).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about an hour of playing (yes, it was super fun) in R, the process
can be better automated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/brycemcd/5d6c9e77cd8597ff7027&quot;&gt;this
gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/brycemcd/5d6c9e77cd8597ff7027.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script produces the following graphs (click to zoom in):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;all-data&quot;&gt;All Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/bme-blog/retention-all.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/bme-blog/retention-all.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;User Retention - All&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;filtered-data&quot;&gt;Filtered Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/bme-blog/retention-filtered.png&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/bme-blog/retention-filtered.png&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; alt=&quot;User Retention - filtered&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;code&gt;X0.weeks.later&lt;/code&gt; isn’t that interesting for this product. So,
it can be cut out by simply subsetting the data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;retention %&amp;gt;% filter(t != &#39;X0.weeks.later&#39; &amp;amp; weeks_ago != 27)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to automatically pull the data into R from the Mixpanel
API. It should be relatively straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This script is certainly going to be useful to me as we continue to
build &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cricketscircle.com&quot;&gt;Cricket’s Circle&lt;/a&gt;. I hope it’s
useful for you as you’re building whatever web or native product you’re
building. Let me know what you’re working on and, as always,
improvements are always welcome. Thanks Dan for the inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>http://www.brycemcdonnell.com/plotting-user-retention-curves-in-R?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_medium=blogrss</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.brycemcdonnell.com/plotting-user-retention-curves-in-R?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_medium=blogrss</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
